#### Contact

+923226475059 (Mobile) the awais@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/awais-raja (LinkedIn)

Top Skills SQL

C#

**JavaScript** 

# Awais Raja

Full Stack Developer | Angular (6 to 10) | React | Redux | Vue.js | .NET Core | .NET 5 | .NET 6 | Blazor.NET | JavaScript | TypeScript | Microservices | Azure | Azure DevOps Lahore District

# Summary

Microsoft Certified Professional with 4 years (4+ years post graduation) of professional experience in solution designing, developing, deploying, testing and debugging of large-scale applications including applications for fortune 500 client with a clear focus on customer needs, business goals, security and scalability.

## My tech stack:

- Web Stack: .NET/.NET CORE, Web API, WCF, C#, EF 5/6,
   Angular, React, Vue, JS, JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML5/CSS3, Signal R
   Core, ADO.NET Core
- Data Stack: Elastic Search, Kibana, SQL, My SQL, PostgreSQL
- Software Engineering Tools: JIRA, VS Team Services, Github, Bitbucket, Azure DevOps
- Cloud-Native: Rabbit MQ, Docker, AWS, Azure, Kubernetes
- DevOps: Jenkins, CI/CD, Github Actions
- Auth: JWT, OAuth, DocuSign, eBay, FB, Google, Insta, KakaoTalk, WeChat

#### During the past 4+ years I've worked with:

- Fortune 500 client on their subsidiary named Perseus which deals in sale/purchase/auction of used vehicles on large scale
- Did code refactoring and Wrote Advanced Unit Tests for Legacy Applications which is being used by IDEAL.
- Large scale medical startup software for intelligent appointment scheduling for patients and providers with the times they wish for with no hustle of scanning through a lot of appointments
- Constellation Software Inc' largest CU organization and its partner businesses on reward-based CU applications

- Contributed to the development of a custom CMS written in .NET that helps small businesses create web pages on simple drag-drop while providing analytics and integrations with 3rd party providers.

My past experiences have helped me develop a good understanding of:

- DB Design
- Software Design Principles (KISS, DRY, YAGNI, SR, IOC)
- Software Design Patterns (CQRS, Mediator, Singleton, Façade, Adapter, Builder, Bridge, etc.)
- Architectural Patterns (Microservices, Layered, Tiers)
- TDD Unit testing (X-Unit & MOQ)
- Real-Time Pushes
- API documentation (Swagger)
- Middleware's
- Performance Improvements
- UI/UX
- Agile, Scrum

I'm a strong believer in giving back to the community which has lead me to speak at 250+ technical sessions, Top 3% last quarter @ Stack Overflow with 2.9M reach (2019) and 100k+ Answer views @ Quora.

I'm currently focused on learning .NET Architecture guide, my Algorithms course at Princeton & MIT (with some math) and System Design and Architecture

Feel free to connect with me here on LinkedIn, Drop me a line at [the.awais@outlook.com]

# Experience

Constellation Software Inc. Software Developer July 2021 - Present (7 months) Pakistan

React Redux and Typescript

- Azure Serverless
- Azure App Services
- .NET Core
- Redis Cache
- Event Grid
- Microservices
- Azure DevOps, Pipelines and VSO and Mono Repo Architecture
- SignalR Service
- Single Sign On
- API Gateways
- Cosmos DB / SQL Server
- XUnit/ NUnit / Automation Testing
- CI/CD Pipelines
- DevOps

#### Borjan (Pvt.) Ltd

Software Developer

September 2019 - July 2021 (1 year 11 months)

Lahore

- Sales
- Import
- Production
- Fixed Asset
- Reporting System (Crystal Reports)
- .NET Framework
- ERP
- Sales
- Accounts and HR
- VB.NET
- SQL Link Servers
- Design Patterns
- Sale Tracking
- Google Maps
- SignalR
- Git, Bitbucket

## Attrayant Designs (PVT LTD)

Software Engineer

September 2017 - September 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Lahore, Pakistan

- ASP.NET MVC
- .NET Framework
- PHP Codelgnitor
- C#, LINQ
- SASS
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Design Patterns
- VueJS
- ChartJS
- SignalR
- Video Call and Conference (Twillio)
- Microsoft SQL Server
- · Git, Bitbucket

Microtechx Internee .Net Develpoer March 2017 - August 2017 (6 months) Lahore, Pakistan

Microtechx is a Microsoft Learning Partner, dealing in training people on Microsoft Certification Tracks.

while working a developer from Jan 2017 - April 2017, I did the following: -contributed to the development of 2 applications for local E Commerce and Training institutes including payment gateways and right management using ASP.NET MVC/EF/SQL

while working as Internee at Microtechx, , I did the following:

- Helped 10+ groups with their FYP
- Help people on Technologies including HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript, Jquery, C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, SQL Server, UI/UX Design Principles.

## Education

Lahore Garrison University

Bachelor's in Computer Science, Computer Science · (2012 - 2016)